What would you wish for?
Three Thousand Years of Longing is a drama, fantasy,
romance film directed by George Miller.
A solitary scholar discovers an ancient bottle while on a trip to
Istanbul and unleashes a djinn who offers her three wishes.
Filled with reluctance, she is unable to come up with one, so
the djinn tries to inspire her with his stories.
Alithea, played by Tilda Swinton.
The Djinn, played by Idris Elba.
Professor Günhan, played by Erdil Yaşaroğlu.
British Council Lady / The Watcher, played by Sabrina Elba.
Airport Djinn, played by Sarah Houbolt.
Pale Djinn, played by Seyithan Özdemir.
Three Thousand Years of Longing is a 2022 romantic fantasy
drama film directed and produced by George Miller.
Written by Miller and Augusta Gore, it is based on the 1994  short
story "The Djinn in the Nightingale's Eye" by A.
Byatt and follows a djinn (Idris Elba) who is unleashed from a bottle by a professor (Tilda
Swinton) and tells her stories from his thousands of years of existence.
The film is dedicated to Miller's mother Angela, as well as Rena
Mitchell, relative of producer Doug Mitchell.
The film premiered out of competition at the 75th
Cannes Film Festival on May 20, 2022.
It was released theatrically in the United States on August 26, 2022, by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures (via
United Artists Releasing), and in Australia on September 1, 2022, by Roadshow Entertainment.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised its visuals and performances,
but was a box-office bomb, grossing $20.3 million against a budget of $60 million.
The film explores themes of mythology, longing, djinn, desire, storytelling.
The tone is emotional.